Hugo Arriojas

Front-End Web Developer

(647)-339-3480 hugo.arriojas@hotmail.com Ottawa,ON

HugoA.dev Github.com/HugoArriojas Linkedin.com/in/HugoArriojas

PROFILE

I am a web developer, accounting administrator, and marine biologist with experience in data analytics, accounting, and customer service roles.

I build accessible, responsive and user-friendly apps in **React**, **jQuery** and **Javascript**.

I'm a committed, attentive, empathetic, detail-oriented team player and I have 3 years of experience working remotely. With my experience in project

management and strong presentation skills, I aim to bring our designs to life.

SKILLS

Web Development

• HTML5 • RESTful APIs

CSS3
 Firebase

SCSS
 Git collaboration

React
 Version Control

Project ScopeFigmaManagementNPM

Accounting

Excel
 ERP Experience

GAAP
 Full-cycle

AR & AP

Data Analytics

• R / RStudio • MATLAB

ANVIOPython

Design & Media

Photoshop
 Lightroom

Premiere Pro

Organization

NotionJIRAADPCDK

LANGUAGES

English - Fluent Spanish - Fluent French - Basic

EDUCATION

Juno College of TechnologySeptember 2021 to December 2021
Web Development Immersive Bootcamp & Javascript Course

Dalhousie University

September 2013 to April 2017

Honours Bachelor of Science in Marine Biology & Statistics

PROJECTS

Reactive Retail

Git, React, SASS, HTML, CSS, Firebase, Figma

- · Mock e-commerse site builtin React using the FakeStore API.
- · Cart items are stored in Firebase
- Users are able to filter through a variety of products via category, and then convert product prices to different currencies.

Live Link: bit.ly/ReactiveRetail **Git Repo:** bit.ly/ReactiveRetailGit

The Not So Social Planner

Git, React, Firebase, HTML, CSS, Figma

- · React project built in agency-style setting from given client brief.
- Social planner where users can submit recurring weekly events into a calendar.
- Users are also able to search what shows are streaming on a particular date if they don't want to go to their social commitments

Live Link: bit.ly/NotSocialPlanner **Git Repo:** bit.ly/NotSocialPlannerGit

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Accounting Administrator

March 2019 to July 2021

Carson Auto Group, Victoria Ford Alliance

- Reviewed and reconciled banking, warranty, and inventory accounts using CDK software, taking care of hundreds of clients spanning 5 large car dealerships.
- Worked with a team to maintain a large database of records using a variety of accounting software in order to track deals, payments, and inventory.
- Spearheaded several projects to increase efficiency in the workplace and aimed to create a standardized method for future workers that may hold the role.
- Used advanced Excel techniques including PivotTables,Vlookup, index/match, and various data tables.

At-Sea Fisheries Observer

January 2018 to November 2018

Archipelago Marine Research

- Gathered, verified, audited, and reported biological and commercial catch data for the Department of Fisheries and Oceans while working in extreme environments.
- Produced detailed & adaptive cruise reports and program summaries while living onboard foreign vessels for extended periods of time.